Guide to the Reproductive Rights National Network records, 1970-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Reproductive Rights National Network records 1970-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Reproductive Rights National Network.
200 items 0.2 linear feet
The Reproductive Rights National Network formed in 1978 in response to the nationwide abortion debate launched by Roe v. Wade. It eventually included about 50 feminist organizations and devoted itself to making reproductive choices available for all women. R2N2 campaigned for safe abortions; for the right of gay couples to adopt and raise children; and against the sterilization of poor or unfit mothers. It disbanded in 1984.
Collection includes an International Planned Parenthood Federation report (Spring 1970); Reproductive Rights National Network newsletters and other coverage of the abortion debate; and administrative materials from the operations of the R2N2, including proposed platforms and policies, clippings and testimonials, and other miscellaneous notes and material. Subjects include abortion rights and protests; birth control; women's sterilization, particularly of Hispanic women; and gay and lesbian rights. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Purchase, 2009 (2009-0077), 0.2 lin. ft.
Historical Note
The Reproductive Rights National Network formed in 1978 in response to the nationwide abortion debate launched by Roe v. Wade. It eventually included about 50 feminist organizations and devoted itself to making reproductive choices available for all women. R2N2 campaigned for safe abortions; for the right of gay couples to adopt and raise children; and against the sterilization of poor or unfit mothers. It disbanded in 1984.
Collection Overview
Collection includes an International Planned Parenthood Federation report (Spring 1970); a Reproductive Rights National Network newsletters; publicity and pamphlets from the abortion debate; and administrative materials from the operations of the R2N2, including proposed platforms and policies, clippings and testimonials, and other miscellaneous notes and materials. Subjects include abortion rights and protests; women's sterilization, particularly of Hispanic women; and gay and lesbian rights. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Sterilization (Birth control)
Birth control
Abortion
Reproductive rights and policy
Reproductive Rights National Network
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Newsletters
Contents of Collection
- Reproductive Rights National Network materials, 1970-1982, (1 box)
  - Abortion Task Force/Human Life amendment, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Conference: R2N2 New York, March 1981
  - Conference and administrative materials, 1980-1982
  - Depo-Provera, 1981
  - Labor movement/Third World women, 1980-1982
  - Publicity: fliers, pamphlets, newsletters, magazine coverage, 1970-1982
  - Rosie Jimenez/Oct. 3 Coalition, 1982
  - Slideshow feedback, Committee to Defend Reproductive Rights, 1981-1982
  - Sterilization abuse, 1980-1982